<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ModMetaData>
  <name>Positive Connections</name>
   <author>cem</author>
  <packageId>cem.PositiveConnections</packageId>
 
  <url>https://github.com/cemacmillan/PositiveConnections</url>
  
  <description>[h1]Positive Connections[/h1]

Are you tired of overseeing colonies where intense animosity prevails among your colonists? 
Despite enduring and conquering numerous shared perils, do they still view each other merely as [i]acquaintances[/i]?

If this resonates with you, then Positive Connections is the mod you've been waiting for.

[h2]Introducing eight brand new **social interactions** for your pawns:[/h2]

[list]
[*]Compliment: Let your colonists express genuine appreciation and admiration for each other's skills and qualities.
[*]Knowledge Sharing: Foster a culture of learning and growth by rewarding your pawns with recognition for sharing their knowledge.
[*]Gift Giving: Strengthen the bonds between your colonists by allowing them to exchange thoughtful gifts, fostering a sense of camaraderie.
[*]Mediation: Settle disputes and conflicts in a civilized manner, promoting harmony and preventing unnecessary tension.
[*]Shared Passions: Unite your colonists through shared hobbies and interests, allowing them to bond over their mutual passions.
[*]Discuss Ideology: Encourage meaningful conversations about ideology and belief systems, fostering understanding and empathy among your colonists.
[*]Comfort: A kind colonist, or one in a good mood at the very least, will seek out another who isn't doing so well and have a chat with them just to see how they are holding up after whatever horrors the Rim has shown them.
[*]Tell Story: Any colonist with a social capacity might tell a story if two others are present.
[/list]

Naturally, rivalries, insults, and pawns stepping over fallen comrades will still occur, just as in the past. However, those who are capable of building positive connections will tend to do so, creating a more harmonious and cohesive colony.

Some of these interactions may occur with pawns from other factions as well, possibly improving diplomatic relations (note: effects on relations are only partly implemented).

[h2]Note:[/h2]

This mod doesn't add any new graphics - only the messages (upper left hand corner) and the pawn's interaction log, memories and mood buffs will tell you what's taking place.

Interactions will sometimes appear in clusters, especially the first few which are triggered. Don't worry. Things will calm back down shortly; it is often transient virtuous-cycles of freshly inspired or uplifted-feeling pawns initiating their own interactions.

Note that "gifts" are ephemeral objects and will not appear in your pawn's inventory.

[h2]Playtesting and Compatibility:[/h2]

Play-tested [strike]hundreds[/strike] many thousands of hours already, but there can always be bugs. Your time in reporting them is appreciated, as are your suggestions.

Combat Extended: Yep.

[h2]Frequently Asked Questions[/h2]

[b]Q: Where are these gifts my colonists are giving each other?[/b]
A: Gifts in Positive Connections are virtual. It's the thought that counts.

[b]Q: Nice, is there a way to shut off notification sounds and the messages? I find it distracting!
A: Enabling [b]Hardcore Mode[/b] will disable all in-game notifications about these events leaving only the interaction bubbles (if enabled) visible. This mode is perfect for those who want to maintain focus without being interrupted by messages, while still benefiting from the positive social dynamics the mod introduces.

[b]Q: Does Positive Connections interact with mod XYZ?[/b]
A: No, Positive Connections uses simple interactions and is agnostic about other mods or DLC (except for our own mods). Once we figure out what to do with "Inhumanized" pawns we'll adjust for that.

[b]Q: What does this gender adjustment switch do?[/b]
A: It should equalize the chances of men or women initiating relationships if activated. This is corrected in the base game now, but we've left it out of nostalgia.

[b]Q: Doesn't this make the game too easy/This barely changes anything?[/b]
A: Everything depends on play style. You can reduce or increase the frequency of interactions from 1/4 to 10x as likely via mod settings. Recommended value is 1. Positive Connections might also encourage you to explore more challenging difficulty settings. For me it allows me to play 1 level higher while still concentrating on building. 

And now you can [b]stop all interactions[/b] via mod options if you feel they are still too frequent [b]without disabling[/b] Positive Connections. 

According to your feedback we'll continue to improve the granularity of control you have over the mod's effects on your game.

[b]Wait... Modders don't play RimWorld anymore, what do you mean 'it allows me to play'?[/b]
A: Yes, I still play every chance I get!

RimWorld is by far my favorite game and favorite game to mod.

[b]Q: Is it possible to request new interactions/a feature where...?[/b]
A: Sure! This mod is under active development and feature requests will be taken into consideration. Most feature additions since the beginning have been due to community suggestions. We want to build new stuff that will make play be more enjoyable, pawns more expressive deep and complex while keeping performance impact trimmed.

[h2]Bugs and Their Ilk[/h2]

Bugs are a natural and inevitable part of software development. If you see any, please be kind and signal them in the appropriate discussion!

You are welcome to support our work on [url=https://ko-fi.com/N4N4NFFPZ]ko-fi.com[/url].

[url=https://ko-fi.com/N4N4NFFPZ][img]https://i.imgur.com/MFApogq.png[/img][/url]

Title Art by Poulpe Voulant.</description>
   <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.4</li>
    <li>1.5</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
</ModMetaData>
